http://jcimn.org/about-us/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Home > About Us > Privacy Policy
JCI Minnesota is a statewide community of young active citizens ages 18-40 who share the belief that in order to create positive change, we must take collective action to improve ourselves and the world around us. Engaging in activities ranging from community development to statewide projects, members demonstrate their social responsibility and improve themselves through participation, leadership and action.
JCI Minnesota is a nonprofit organization that is supported by voluntary contributions from members and friends of JCI Minnesota who share a vision for a better Minnesota.
In the course of fulfilling its mission of supporting local chapters located throughout the state of Minnesota, the organization collects personal information regarding the individuals it serves. JCI Minnesota is committed to maintaining the privacy of these individuals.
JCI Minnesota has adopted this privacy statement to affirm this commitment and to assure transparency in how it collects, retains and uses personal information.
What is personal information?
Personal information is information that identifies and describes a JCI Minnesota member or other individual, including but not limited to name, contact information, date of birth and email address.
Why JCI MN collects personal information:
-Financial processing, including, but not limited to, billing and payments.
-Supporting the Minnesota Jaycees Foundation, including, but not limited to, fund development, grants, awards, recognition and promotion, tracking membership trends, identifying JCI Minnesota members for advancement to leadership positions and supporting membership renewals.
-Communicating key organizational messages through state publications and appropriate JCI, National and Local officers.
-Facilitating the planning and operation of state conventions and other meetings and special events.
-Supporting and further developing programs and activities.
-Facilitating participation in programs and activities.
-Communicating information to non-JCI MN members, including, but not limited to, alumni, partners and licensees.
When JCI MN may disclose personal information to others
JCI Minnesota may disclose personal information about members and other individuals to others as necessary to facilitate the purposes of JCI Minnesota. This may include activities such as mailing newsletters/updates, communicating with local members or officers, or connecting members of the community to a local chapter.
JCI MN may also disclose personal information when:
-Such information is already otherwise available to the public.
-Such disclosure may be required by law.
-When necessary to protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of an individual or group.
Protection of Personal Information
JCI Minnesota will implement appropriate controls to monitor and assure compliance with this privacy policy, including the utilization of reasonable security measures to prevent unauthorized access to or inappropriate use of personal information. JCI Minnesota will immediately respond to any unauthorized access to or inappropriate use of personal information or any other violation of this Privacy Policy.
Personal Information on www.jcimn.org
JCI Minnesota will protect the security of personal information on jcimn.org by using password-protected areas and other appropriate security measures. JCI Minnesota will restrict access to personal information available on jcimn.org to appropriate persons.
Accuracy of Personal Information
JCI Minnesota will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information it retains is accurate. JCI Minnesota will provide reasonable access to individuals seeking to confirm or correct their personal information.
JCI MN Privacy Policy
In its effort to ensure that JCI Minnesota is following appropriate privacy standards, JCI Minnesota will periodically review and update as appropriate its Privacy Policy.
